Many saw evil. They dared to stop it.
Valkyrie is a drama, thriller, war film directed by Bryan Singer.
Wounded in Africa during World War II, Nazi Col.
Claus von Stauffenberg returns to his native Germany and joins the Resistance in a
daring plan to create a shadow government and assassinate Adolf Hitler.
When events unfold so that he becomes a central player, he finds himself tasked
with both leading the coup and personally killing the Führer.
Claus Schenk Graf von Stauffenberg, played by Tom Cruise.
Henning von Tresckow, played by Kenneth Branagh.
Friedrich Olbricht, played by Bill Nighy.
Ludwig Beck, played by Terence Stamp.
Friedrich Fromm, played by Tom Wilkinson.
Nina Schenk Gräfin von Stauffenberg, played by Carice van Houten.
Valkyrie (German: Walküre, as featured in the opening sequence) is a 2008 historical thriller film directed
by Bryan Singer, written by Christopher McQuarrie and Nathan Alexander, starring Tom Cruise.
The film is set in Nazi Germany during World War II and depicts the 20 July plot in 1944 by German army officers to
assassinate Adolf Hitler and to use the Operation Valkyrie national emergency plan to take control of the country.
The film was released by American studio United Artists and stars Cruise as
Colonel Claus von Stauffenberg, one of the key plotters.
The supporting cast includes Kenneth Branagh, Bill Nighy,
Eddie Izzard, Terence Stamp, and Tom Wilkinson.
Cruise's casting caused controversy among German politicians and members of the von Stauffenberg family
due to the actor's practice of Scientology, which is viewed with suspicion in Germany.
Because of this, the filmmakers initially had difficulty setting up filming locations in Germany,
but they were later given access to locations such as Berlin's historic Bendlerblock.
German newspapers and filmmakers supported the film and its intention
to spread global awareness of von Stauffenberg's plot.
The film changed release dates several times, from as early as
June 27, 2008, to as late as February 13, 2009.
The changing calendar and poor response to United Artists's initial marketing campaign drew criticism about the film's viability; following a positive test
screening, Valkyrie's release in North America was ultimately changed to December 25, 2008, and it opened in Germany on January 22, 2009.
United Artists renewed its marketing campaign to reduce its focus
on Cruise and to highlight Singer's credentials.
The film received generally positive reviews from
critics and grossed $201 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of friendship, suicide, plan,
berlin, germany, husband wife relationship.
The tone is emotional and intense.